Danielle Frappier

SHE | HER

I love to create beautiful web applications and user experiences. I have successfully helped organizations deploy scalable design systems, web applications and CMS driven websites that improve SEO, lead generation and online presence.

(508) 574.0944 daniellerichard1@gmail.com daniellefrappier.com

EXPERIENCE

Monster — Senior Systems Design Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Team lead for Randstad Brand Design System. Responsible for mentoring junior engineers, establishing code standards and best practices and making decisions on the architecture of the design system.
- Built React component library with TypeScript & Styled Components, wrote unit tests using Jest and React Testing Library and documented components in Storybook.
- Provided support for monster.com homepage built using Gatsby.

John Hancock — Front End Engineer

JANUARY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Sole developer for web applications used by Sales, Marketing and Education departments to sell, promote and onboard clients and new users
- Developed web applications using AngularJS and ReactJS/Context API.
- Responsible for adding future forward functionality to applications and maintaining code bases.
- Accountable for QA and release process for all assigned web applications.

Applause — Front End Developer

NOVEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2019

- Lead migration and development of applause.com from contentful/middleman to CraftCMS.
- Identified areas on applause.com not accessible WCAG 2.0 compliant and implemented changes to correct.
- Implemented new landing pages and emails in Marketo.

WHERE YOU CAN FIND ME

linkedin.com/in/daniellefrappier github.com/daniellefrappier18 codepen.io/daniellefrapp jsfiddle.net/user/daniellefrappier

TECH STACK

JavaScript

TypeScript, ReactJS/Context API, Styled Components, Jest, React Testing Library, AngularJS

CMS & Static Site Generators

Gatsby, CraftCMS, Contentful, Wordpress, ExpressionEngine, Middleman, Jekyll

Build Tools

Lerna, Yarn Workspaces, Jenkins, Spinnaker, Sonarqube, Webpack Gulp, GIT

Workshop Environments

Storybook, PatternLab

The Other Stuff

SCSS, LESS, TWIG, Figma, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator

WHAT I DO OUTSIDE OF WORK

Surfing, Snowboarding, Knitting and Crocheting, Sci-fi movies, reading post-apocalyptic novels

Aetna — *UX Designer/Developer*

SEPTEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

Created landing page and email templates to be WCAG 2.0 compliant.

EH Media — Senior Web Designer/Developer

OCTOBER 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2017

- Designed and implemented new functionality that led to engaging product offerings and generated new revenue.
- Ensured high-performance and availability of multiple WordPress sites.
- Created WordPress themes and plugins for non-technical content creators within the company to easily publish new content while adhering to company and web best practices.

ACIS Educational Tours — Web Designer/Developer

MARCH 2013 - OCTOBER 2015

- Lead designer and developer for three brands: www.acis.com, www.encoretours.com, www.goplay-sports.com.
- Designed and developed landing pages and emails in Marketo, Hubspot, and ClickDimensions.
- Designed trade show booths, print materials, infographics and Ebooks.

MEDITECH — Supervisor of Web Design

OCTOBER 2006 - MARCH 2013

- Promoted three times during tenure. Previous positions held were: Senior Web Designer and Graphic Designer.
- Responsible for the successful delivery and execution of web design projects for public web presence, corporate events, and customer focused web magazine with a team of 5 designers.
- Identified and led migration from home-grown CMS to Drupal which provided the company a more efficient and modern publishing platform to deliver sales, marketing and company collateral to new and existing customers.
- Designed custom sales demos for proposals above \$1 million dollars.

EDUCATION

Framingham State University — BA, Graphic Design

2001 - 2006

Minors in Computer Science and Communication Arts